<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Vapor Story</title>
  
  <subtitle>We come for your loot.</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://nvn.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-09-11T23:44:17.889Z</updated>
  <id>http://nvn.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>nihiven</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Pastel Future</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/09/11/Pastel-Future/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/09/11/Pastel-Future/</id>
    <published>2018-09-11T23:59:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-11T23:44:17.889Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been working on a world that takes place in an alternate 2005. In this version of the world, the 90s were not the decade of grunge, blonde tips did not exist, and Pulp Fiction was a neon-noir film masterpiece. On the eve of Y2K, instead of hiding in their basements with a two year supply of canned food, people jack in and build a collective experience that accelerates the world’s technology growth exponentially.</p><p>Steve Jobs introduces the Apple Watch over a decade earlier than we are used to. It includes a feature that covers you in a protective pill shapped bubble from head to toe; very important when Infection is on the rise! Meanwhile, Quantel combines forces with Lecktrik Systems to create the world’s first line of smart clothing, with Cell Touch technology.</p><p>Miami Vice is longest running show of all-time and Don Johnson is the highest paid actor in the world. Jan Hammer tops the charts on an annual basis. What a world!</p><h2 id="Telling-a-Story"><a href="#Telling-a-Story" class="headerlink" title="Telling a Story"></a>Telling a Story</h2><p>I’ve written some short stories before, but nothing on the scale of this game. I have a lot of threads that I need to tie together. The story is a variation on the Hero’s Journey:</p><blockquote><p>In narratology and comparative mythology, the monomyth, or the hero’s journey, is the common template of a broad category of tales that involve a hero who goes on an adventure, and in a decisive crisis wins a victory, and then comes home changed or transformed.</p></blockquote><p>You can read more about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hero%27s_journey" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Hero’s Journey on Wikipedia</a>.</p><h2 id="Black-Market-Clothing"><a href="#Black-Market-Clothing" class="headerlink" title="Black Market Clothing"></a>Black Market Clothing</h2><p>The first quest in the works has you getting involved in the black market. In our new world, certain types of clothing are banned because of how they are used in the world of recreational drugs. This particular item that you are searching for has a combination of Cell Touch and Quantel properties, which allow it two do two things:</p><ul><li>Transport matter from a remote broadcast system to the garment’s internal molecular delivery system.</li><li>Transfer matter and data into the skin at the molecular level.</li></ul><p> Enterprising parties use these two properties to facilitate the remote delivery of illicit substances. A string of underground clubs are built around the use of this type of clothing. These clubs are very exclusive and highly illegal. Your client wants to obtain some of the clothing required to attend such clubs and since she has something you need, you’re on the hook to find something she can wear.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on a world that takes place in an alternate 2005. In this version of the world, the 90s were not the decade of grunge, 
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="story" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/story/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Summer in the City</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/08/29/Summer-in-the-City/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/08/29/Summer-in-the-City/</id>
    <published>2018-08-29T19:45:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-29T18:48:07.015Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m using a set of modular city assests to mock up a sample map. I’m going to set up some interactions with some city-dwellers and work on some quest stuff with them. Maybe there is a gunsmith to build me a Sleeper?</p><p><img src="/images/Sci-Fi-city-samples.jpg" alt="Vapor City?"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I’m using a set of modular city assests to mock up a sample map. I’m going to set up some interactions with some city-dwellers and work o
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="art design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/art-design/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The TODO List</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/08/21/The-TODO-List/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/08/21/The-TODO-List/</id>
    <published>2018-08-21T23:02:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-22T03:14:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Project Management</strong><br>I love lists. They keep me on track and they let me dump stuff out of my head so I have some room to think. Trello helps me make lists, so I love Trello and it’s simple and straight-forward design. I had more things to say about Trello, but I forget them before I could make a list.</p><div align="center"><img src="/images/trello-20180821.png" alt="The TODO List"></div><p><strong>Tech Design</strong><br>I’m building item pickup functionality, using the voxel Sleeper Simulant to test. Here are the object so far, each lower level object is a sub-class of the object above it:</p><ul><li>Pickup Primal<ul><li>Pickup Weapon Primal<ul><li>Pickup Weapon Sleeper Simulant</li></ul></li><li>Pickup Bonus Primal<ul><li>Pickup Bonus GloDots</li><li>Pickup Bonus Credits</li></ul></li><li>Pickup Ammo Primal<ul><li>Pickup Ammo Primary</li><li>Pickup Ammo Precision</li><li>Pickup Ammo Heavy</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>Primal objects must be sub-classed. The <strong>Pickup Weapon Primal</strong> describes the weapon and defines available properties (reserve size, clip size, equip speed, mesh, icon, etc) and <strong>Pickup Weapon Sleeper Simulant</strong> defines the values for these properties. This is pretty standard <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-oriented_programming" target="_blank" rel="noopener">object-oriented programming</a>. The amazing part to me is how intuitive it is to implement this design within the Unreal engine. Here’s a sample of the Sleeper’s item popup:</p><table><tbody><tr><td><img src="/images/examiningSleeper.jpg" alt=""></td><td><img src="/images/examiningSleeper2.jpg" alt=""></td></tr></tbody></table><p>These entries always take me longer to write than I think they will. I’m going to do one every three days or so.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;I love lists. They keep me on track and they let me dump stuff out of my head so I have some room 
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tech design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/tech-design/"/>
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="unreal" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/unreal/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Pill Baxton</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/08/19/Pill-Baxton/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/08/19/Pill-Baxton/</id>
    <published>2018-08-20T00:23:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-19T23:46:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a dream not too long ago about a scene from Weird Sciene. It’s the one where Chet is berating Wyatt in the hallway after Gary’s night on the town. There was a lot of weird stuff going on though. Colors were strange and vivid, things were moving around. It reminded me of <a href="/2018/02/18/Dream-State-Pittsburgh/" title="this other dream I had about Pittsburgh">this other dream I had about Pittsburgh</a>. I did my best to represent it in the picture below.</p><div align="center"><img src="/images/PillBaxton.jpg" alt="ｐｉｌｌ_ｂａｘｔｏｎ"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I had a dream not too long ago about a scene from Weird Sciene. It’s the one where Chet is berating Wyatt in the hallway after Gary’s nig
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="art design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/art-design/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>GlitchRock Logo</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/08/18/GlitchRock-Logo/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/08/18/GlitchRock-Logo/</id>
    <published>2018-08-18T16:41:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:16:55.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m working on a logo for GlitchRock Games. I want something that is simple and kind of retro, recognizable, and related to the GlitchRock name in literal way. I like the idea of this simple outline of a rock. The original GlitchRock was taken from a game screenshot, Call of Duty or something like that. The idea of having it glitched out is kind of cool. I can see the simple rock being a good watermark, but as a logo, it’s missing something. Will anyone know what it is unless it’s used in conjuction with the name? Maybe it needs some shading or something.</p><table><tbody><tr><td><img src="/images/TheOriginalGlitchRock.png" alt="OG GlitchRock"></td><td><img src="/images/theRock.png" alt="Your basic GlitchRock"></td><td><img src="/images/GlitchRock-glitchy.png" alt="Glitchy GlitchRock"></td></tr></tbody></table><div align="center"><img src="/images/bigLogo.png" alt="Sample Logo Card"></div><br>&nbsp;<br><hr><br><br><strong>ArtStation</strong><br><a href="http://artstation.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ArtStation</a> is a site where profession artists post portfolios of their work. There is so much amazing there. I made <a href="https://www.artstation.com/nihiven/collections/362611" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a collection of inspirationl pictures</a> for Vapor Story. These all have some element of asthetic I want. A lot of the artists on this site are available for hire. I need to start saving my pennies.<br><br><div align="center"><img src="https://cdnb.artstation.com/p/assets/images/images/004/547/073/large/jugoslav-stankin-cyberpunkish.jpg?1484493821" alt="New retro wave-ish city"></div><br><div align="center"><img src="https://cdnb.artstation.com/p/assets/images/images/009/644/353/large/daniele-caviglia-scifi-city-post.jpg?1520117039" alt="ｃｉｔｙ_ｓｃｅｎｅ"></div><br><div align="center"><img src="https://cdna.artstation.com/p/assets/images/images/012/389/894/large/eugenio-garcia-villarreal-hh.jpg?1534536864" alt="Cyberpunk 2025"></div><br><div align="center"><img src="https://cdna.artstation.com/p/assets/images/images/007/082/334/large/vera-lee-disgusting.jpg?1503542272" alt="Wild World"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I’m working on a logo for GlitchRock Games. I want something that is simple and kind of retro, recognizable, and related to the GlitchRoc
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="glitchrock games" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/glitchrock-games/"/>
    
    
      <category term="art design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/art-design/"/>
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="unreal" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/unreal/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Nah man, it&#39;s August</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/08/17/Nah-man-it-s-August/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/08/17/Nah-man-it-s-August/</id>
    <published>2018-08-17T19:59:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T20:15:47.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Website</strong><br>I am finally DONE with the site redesign. I’m done writing posts in straight html! This site now runs on <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hexo</a> and has the basic features of a blog. Categories, tags, archive, history… I’m so happy that’s done. Every time I wanted to write a post, I would think about how I still haven’t made a new page for June posts and then I’d think of HTML and then… no post. This is the first post using the new system! There are still some little bugs to work out and I’ll be doing that in the next couple of days.</p><p><strong>Vapor Story</strong><br>I told myself when I started this game that I wanted to make the game I had in my mind. I would not compromise on some part of the design because it was too hard, or would take too long.  Then when I chose GameMaker, that’s exactly what I was doing. I said to myself that an Unreal based game would be too hard. I didn’t have the experience I needed. It will take forever. Then I started with GameMaker and got far enough along in the design that I realized I just didn’t like what I was making. It really hit home when I started playing through Hyper Light Drifter and I couldn’t get into it. I wasn’t having a good time and it was because the game was 2d. It  was flat. You can’t look out over the land. You can’t see things off in the distance and decide to go to them. I want that for my game. So, I picked up Unreal. I took an introduction course and built some sample levels. It’s been a lot of work, but I think it’s right. I like what I’m making.</p><p>Using Unreal engine means that for now, the game is a first person shooter. That is awesome…!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;I am finally DONE with the site redesign. I’m done writing posts in straight html! This site now runs on &lt;a h
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="unreal" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/unreal/"/>
    
      <category term="website" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/website/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Still Alive?</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/07/01/Still-Alive/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/07/01/Still-Alive/</id>
    <published>2018-07-01T19:57:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:58:29.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m still alive! Game progress is slow, but continues. Vapor Story is coming to life!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I’m still alive! Game progress is slow, but continues. Vapor Story is coming to life!&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Destiny 2</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/05/20/Destiny-2/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/05/20/Destiny-2/</id>
    <published>2018-05-20T19:56:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:57:30.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just had my birthday! I’ve been playing a lot of Destiny 2 on PC lately. I’m a little bit out of the development loop, but that’s ok. I needed a little break after five straight months. I plan on making a big push this coming weekend. I’ll have some down time and will be in a nice quiet place.</p><p>I’m going to be working on item generation, stats, properties, etc… I want to be able to equip items and have their properties affect the player. I also want to get battle working. SHOOTING stuff. LET’S GO!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I just had my birthday! I’ve been playing a lot of Destiny 2 on PC lately. I’m a little bit out of the development loop, but that’s ok. I
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="destiny" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/destiny/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>That&#39;s all we&#39;ve done?</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/04/27/That-s-all-we-ve-done/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/04/27/That-s-all-we-ve-done/</id>
    <published>2018-04-27T19:56:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:47:36.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Technical Design</strong><br>It’s a been an unproductive week at GlitchRock Games. I suffer from anxiety/migraines and neither of them have been very kind to me this week. I’ve lost the whole week to them. I’m working as much as I can today and hopefully will be back at full steam tomorrow. In the last few sessions, I’ve worked on sorting out the inventory, tweaking some things here and there, and making some changes to make it feel a lot like the system from Diablo 3. I’m doing stacking a little differently, but aside from that, it’s very similar.</p><p>I’m going to take a little time to work on character movement now. It feels sluggish and boring. Adding a nice effect to the dash and tweaking the collision code will make it feel a lot more solid and responsive. This will tie in to adding the controller as an input device. Right now, you can only move with the keyboard and mouse. The input system is made up off two layers; input reading and action mapping. The input module reads all available inputs and maps them to a given action, which will eventually be assigned through the Input Configuration menu. An input to action mapping looks something like: action_map[action.attack] = input.mb_left;</p><p>This type of mapping lets me reference the actions in the game code, instead of specific keys. It’s a common technique and allows for user control customization. I’m a big fan of customization and options, so I’m working on exposing as many options as is appropriate.</p><p>ps. I stole the screen shake code that I used in Poopin in Swoopin and made it an object in Vapor Story.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;It’s a been an unproductive week at GlitchRock Games. I suffer from anxiety/migraines and neither of
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tech design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/tech-design/"/>
    
      <category term="irl" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/irl/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Poopin&#39; and Swoopin&#39;</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/04/23/Poopin-and-Swoopin/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/04/23/Poopin-and-Swoopin/</id>
    <published>2018-04-23T19:52:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:55:19.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took a little break from Vapor Story this weekend to work on a game for <a href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/41" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ludum Dare 41</a>. The theme was ‘combine two incompatible genres’ and my game was a castle defense + farming sim, called Swoopin and Poopin. I code  pretty slowly, so I didn’t get finished, but I plan to work on it when I need a break from VS.</p><div align="center"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VL3B-D_u7aA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I took a little break from Vapor Story this weekend to work on a game for &lt;a href=&quot;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/41&quot; target=&quot;_blank
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="game jam" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/game-jam/"/>
    
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="ludum dare" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/ludum-dare/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Friday the 13th</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/04/13/Friday-the-13th/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/04/13/Friday-the-13th/</id>
    <published>2018-04-13T19:50:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:46:01.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Notes</strong><br>I’ve gotten the inventory working somewhat. There is a video of that down below. There is also a world clock, which is used to cycle day night coloring. It’s just a simple overlay now, I’m not even sure the game will have day and night.</p><div style="width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.250%;"><iframe src="https://streamable.com/s/7ni2n/uuejom" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="100%" allowfullscreen style="width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;"></iframe></div><br><div align="center"><img src="/images/jv.gif" alt="YES!"></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;I’ve gotten the inventory working somewhat. There is a video of that down below. There is also a world clock, w
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
      <category term="holiday" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/holiday/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Spaghetti Code</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/04/08/Spaghetti-Code/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/04/08/Spaghetti-Code/</id>
    <published>2018-04-08T19:46:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:49:58.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Techinical Design</strong><br>This weekend has been great as far as progress is concerned. Although, I’ve noticed that I’m just kind of throwing code all over the place. Some of it is getting a bit wild and is all over the place. I’m taking some time to reel those parts in, as well as correcting and expanding on some things;<br>naming of variables and scripts, including tree locations</p><ul><li>collision: this hasn’t worked correctly since I changed the main character sprite</li><li>data structure: I am making objects for each item and that’s not working out. I’m going to set up an item index and build objects based on the index data instead of building the data into the objects. I’ll have to think about how code works for unqiue items.</li><li>animation: it’s working ok as is. It needs a little more flexibility for layering items on top of each other. I want to setup parts for characters (head, torso, legs, etc…) and be able to assign items to those parts.</li><li>drawing: I need to make a system to control drawing order. The sprites are drawn in whatever order Game Maker draws them in. This leads to some items being drawn on top of things they shouldn’t be. I need keep a depth order and draw based on that.</li></ul><p>I’m not going to beat myself up over these thinsg, I’ll look at it as learning the ropes of Game Maker. Also, I’m pretty happy with the way input is handled and abstracted. The extra time spent on that will allow for custom input mapping and it’s easy to use in code.</p><p><strong>Game Design</strong><br>I’m playing through Breath of the Wild on Master Mode. There are times when I’m totally ignoring the story or any quest and I just go around in my stealth gear collecting beetles. This is the kind of activity I want to have in my game. Something that is fun and beneficial to the player, despite being totally optional. I would love for the players to be able to take pictures, or something with a similar purpose (tagging different game objects). I’m thinking about that a lot.</p><p>The story is still a work in progress. I aim for it to be something that can stand alone and be enjoyable on its own. I like it a lot so far.</p><p>This is a picture of the inventory window. The dark gray slots are disabled and can be unlocked through perks or experience.<br><img src="/images/180408-Inventory.png" alt="Inventory Window"></p><p>ps. <a href="https://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/134949/learning_from_the_masters_level_.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This article on The Legend of Zelda level design</a> is pretty good!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Techinical Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;This weekend has been great as far as progress is concerned. Although, I’ve noticed that I’m just k
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tech design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/tech-design/"/>
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="botw" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/botw/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Inventory Popup</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/04/03/Inventory-Popup/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/04/03/Inventory-Popup/</id>
    <published>2018-04-03T19:28:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:48:49.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is the beginning of the inventory popup and picking up items.</p><div style="width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.250%;"><iframe src="https://streamable.com/s/cszk7/doelra" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="100%" allowfullscreen style="width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;"></iframe></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Here is the beginning of the inventory popup and picking up items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Happy Easter</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/04/01/Happy-Easter/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/04/01/Happy-Easter/</id>
    <published>2018-04-01T09:23:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T19:10:38.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div align="center"><img src="/images/happyEaster.gif"><br><strong>Happy Easter from GlitchRock Games!</strong></div></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/happyEaster.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy Easter from GlitchRock Games!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Holidays!" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/Holidays/"/>
    
    
      <category term="holiday" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/holiday/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Doom Article</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/03/28/DooM-Article/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/03/28/DooM-Article/</id>
    <published>2018-03-28T19:14:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:20:04.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/295254/Make_me_think_make_me_move_New_Dooms_deceptively_simple_design.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This article on Gamasutra</a> about the design process behind <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doom_%282016_video_game%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Doom 2016</a> is really interesting.</p><blockquote><p>Here’s how Stratton and id creative director Hugo Martin defined the idea of “combat chess”: speed of movement; individuality of the demons; distinctiveness of the weapons; overall power of the player; and the idea of “make me think, make me move.”</p></blockquote><p>On gameplay…</p><blockquote><p>Martin added, “We just edited a lot of stuff, and said we don’t necessarily want the player to have multiple ways to accomplish their goals – there’s only one way to play Doom…We cut a lot of stuff that is completely valid in a lot of [other] games, just to get the game to feel like Doom.”</p></blockquote><p>No reloading, it’s DOOM!</p><blockquote><p>Doom cuts the cruft from the modern first-person shooter format. There’s relatively little dialog, there are “missing” mechanics like reloading, and the tools provided to players in order to progress require little overt explanation or tutorializing.</p></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/295254/Make_me_think_make_me_move_New_Dooms_deceptively_simple_design.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; r
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="doom" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/doom/"/>
    
      <category term="article" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/article/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Item Popups</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/03/26/Item-Popups/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/03/26/Item-Popups/</id>
    <published>2018-03-26T19:12:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:52:33.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stopping in to drop off a video of the item popups!</p><div style="width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.250%;"><iframe src="https://streamable.com/s/e6h18/nxmebw" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="100%" allowfullscreen style="width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;"></iframe></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Stopping in to drop off a video of the item popups!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.250%
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="art design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/art-design/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Camera Perspective</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/03/18/Camera-Perspective/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/03/18/Camera-Perspective/</id>
    <published>2018-03-18T19:03:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:48:27.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Technical Design</strong><br>Holy hell, March is half over! I’m picking at things, trying this, that… mostly to see how Game Maker works and what’s possible. I did something with the background sky that’s been behind the buildings in many of the videos below, replacing it with a shader instead of a texture. It works really well. If the shader was some type of cloudy sky, it would look a lot like the sky in Breath of the Wild, which is definitely a dynamic shader. Something a lot like this…</p><iframe width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" src="https://www.shadertoy.com/embed/Mtd3W7?gui=true&t=10&paused=true&muted=false" allowfullscreen></iframe><p><strong>Game Design</strong><br>One of the problems I’m having is how to handle the camera perspective. Think of a first or third person game, when the camera is low to the ground and you can see off into the distance. When the camera is high, you are above the player, staring down at the ground. These pictures illustrate the difference. These are all pictures of the same scene, with only the camera’s height changing.</p><table><tbody><tr><td><img src="/images/botwLowCamera.jpg" alt="Directly Behind"></td><td><img src="/images/botwMedCamera.png" alt="Behind High"></td><td><img src="/images/botwHighCamera.png" alt="Overhead"></td></tr></tbody></table><p>In my opinion, the first one looks the best and the third the worst. My game is a top down game, which is a lot like the third picture. My dilemma is: How do I make something that looks more like the first picture, than it does the third? The awesome feeling that I get from being able to stand atop a big mountain and look out over the landscape can’t be overstated. I don’t know that it’s possible to replicate that feeling in a 2d world though. In an attempt to replicate the low camera look, you can zoom out, which will increase the field of view. This relieves some of the claustraphobic feeling from the third picture. If that view was zoomed out, allowing you to see the sorroundings, it would be a little more playable. I tried this with my protoype and zoomed the camera out around 100%. It gives a much larger field of view and feels a little more substantial, which you can see in the video below.</p><div style="width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.250%;"><iframe src="https://streamable.com/s/3sotf/doaahy" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="100%" allowfullscreen style="width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;"></iframe></div><p>I’m going to keep experimenting. I’ll check out some other games to see how they handle it, as I’m sure someone already has a great solution.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Holy hell, March is half over! I’m picking at things, trying this, that… mostly to see how Game Make
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="art design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/art-design/"/>
    
      <category term="tech design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/tech-design/"/>
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="botw" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/botw/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
      <category term="shader" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/shader/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Shader Work</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/03/15/Shader-Work/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/03/15/Shader-Work/</id>
    <published>2018-03-15T19:01:28.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:03:21.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight, I’m working on something a little different for me. I need a ‘scan’ effect for when the ghost highlights something, which seems like something I can do with shaders. I’ve never used shaders before, so I’m looking at <a href="http://xorshaders.weebly.com/tutorials/converting-sandbox-shaders" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this tutorial</a> to help me out. This <a href="https://www.shadertoy.com/view/ldjGzV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VCR distortion shader</a> is out of control! I’m looking to do something like this <a href="https://www.shadertoy.com/view/Xs3SWH" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scanning shader</a>.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Tonight, I’m working on something a little different for me. I need a ‘scan’ effect for when the ghost highlights something, which seems 
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="shader" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/shader/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Work Log</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/03/13/Work-Log/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/03/13/Work-Log/</id>
    <published>2018-03-13T18:59:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-17T18:00:18.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you don’t see any updates for a while, check my <a href="/work.txt">Work Log</a>. I keep it updated with technical stuff, some ideas, to do lists, upcoming objects, etc. Sometimes I don’t have much to say and don’t want to make a post here just to say I’m still around. I’ve added a link at the top of all pages.</p><p>Testing refined ghost movement.</p><div style="width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.250%;"><iframe src="https://streamable.com/s/1z7mu/bbjczz" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="100%" allowfullscreen style="width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;"></iframe></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;If you don’t see any updates for a while, check my &lt;a href=&quot;/work.txt&quot;&gt;Work Log&lt;/a&gt;. I keep it updated with technical stuff, some ideas, 
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Little Light</title>
    <link href="http://nvn.io/2018/03/12/Little-Light/"/>
    <id>http://nvn.io/2018/03/12/Little-Light/</id>
    <published>2018-03-12T18:51:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-08-18T17:51:20.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Technical Design</strong><br>GameMaker really works well when it comes to reuseability. I will code something directly on the player object, the code to initialize the sound emitters for instance, then refactor that code into a function that accepts the target object as a parameter. This isn’t groundbreaking or anything. The great part is the way GameMaker facilitates this type of design and makes it easy to do. It agrees with my style very much.</p><p>Let’s get to some specific things I’m working on…</p><p><strong>The Player</strong><br>The main character was originally written as a guy like me named Elliot Ever. However, this quickly lead to me referring to the world as the Eververse, which is not good. I’m not sure what to name him now. I was thinking of letting the player name the character and not referring to the character by any specific gender. This way, the person playing the game can pour themself into the main character container and not feel out of place. I’d like anyone to be able to imagine that if they were put in the hero’s place, they could fill the role very well!</p><p>Not having a specific character to work with got me thinking about the hero’s interactions with other characters in the game. How would a hero with no personality decide what to say, what to do? So I decided to give the hero a personality type, akin to how the hero is defined in Just Cause 3. Rico Rodriguez has a very well defined personality and set of needs.</p><blockquote><p>“The child of one thousand comic books and action movies. He is James Bond, Mad Max, Jason Bourne, El Mariachi, Wolverine, Punisher, Rambo, Tony Montana and Han Solo all rolled into one. With a touch of Enrique Iglesias to top it all off!”</p></blockquote><p>I’ve thought about giving the hero a personality that is loosely based on one of the Myers-Briggs types, speficially, INTP. That’s probably where I will start as far as interactions go.</p><p><strong>Little Buddy</strong><br>I wanted to have a buddy companion for the player. Think, Destiny’s Ghost, Halo’s Cortana, or System Shock’s SHODAN. I picture the companion traveling with the player like the Ghost, giving the player real-time augmented reality feedback. For instance, when you walk up to an NPC, the companion will display the active quests involving that NPC. How or where these would be displayed is unknown.</p><p>GameMaker works in such a way that I will code the logic for these augmented reality components into the companion’s game object. They will activate and deactivate based soley on the Ghost’s presence in the world and will operate entirely independent of any other object in the game. The ghost requires a follow target, in our case it’s the player. From that follow object, the ghost gets the viewport and uses that to display its augmented reality information. You could attach it to any object with an active viewport and it would display its information correctly.</p><p>I liked the Ghost idea until I played Hyper Light Drifter and saw their Ghost. That game already has so many similarities to mine that adding a ghost just seems like it will invite even more comparison. Part of me doesn’t care about the similarities. I’ve known about the type of game I want to make for 10 years and that’s what I’m going to make. Another part of me says, get rid of the ghost, get rid of the work required to make the ghost. I’m leaning towards an in-ear companion, much like <a href="http://enderverse.wikia.com/wiki/Jane" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jane</a> from the Ender book, “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speaker_for_the_Dead" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Speaker for the Dead</a>.”</p><div style="width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 117.647%;"><iframe src="https://streamable.com/s/lewkw/wflejq" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="100%" allowfullscreen style="width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" alt="Samus"></iframe></div><p><strong>The Game World</strong><br><strong>Earth</strong><br>This has been tough for me. I want so badly to integrate unexplained real world events into my story, explaining them as consequences of the game’s events. It just doesn’t seem like it’s going to line up. I will take another pass at it though, I really enjoyed writing those parts of the story.</p><p><strong>Roma</strong><br>The ‘alien’ world is called Roma in everything I’ve written. Inhabited by Romans, which aren’t from Romania. They are ‘robotic human.’ Not really robotic at all, but that’s how we can understand them from our frame of reference.</p><p><strong>Romans</strong><br>They are a lot like we could be a few hundred years from now. Their planet is dying and has recently reach the tipping point. They disregarded any concern for the planet because they had an extremely advanced space program. It was very nearly ready to support a full blown planet-wide emigration when they were attacked on a global scale. The assailant, an alien race that frequented the Solar system, was thought to be an ally and attacked with little resistance. By the time the Romans were able to respond, the war had already been lost. The Romans presence in space was nearly wiped out when the capital spaceport, Porta De Ceu, was totally destroyed. Millions died in the unprovoked attack.</p><p><strong>Collusion and the Altayih</strong><br>Once the dust had settled from the invasion, It was found that many Romans had colluded with the Altayih to ensure the effectiveness of the attack. These traitors, known as Tamurins, were critical to the Altayin’s understanding of the Roman defenses, helping to detail and map out the Roman response to the surprise attack. The Roman’s faith and trust in the Altayih was mirrored by the Tamurins, and they too were betrayed. The Tamurins were promised positions of power once the Romans were conquered, but few survived the attacks and many were executed by their co-conspirators. Within a few weeks, the Altayin’s had taken control of every one of the Romans offworld mines. They enslaved the inhabitants of the mining colonies and eventually worked many of the colonists to death. It turned out that the Altayih had no desire to conquer the Romans and were merely doing what had to be done to collect as many resources as they could. After a few decades, the Altayih moved on to a new system.</p><p>This goes on and on…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;GameMaker really works well when it comes to reuseability. I will code something directly on the pla
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="vapor game" scheme="http://nvn.io/categories/vapor-game/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tech design" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/tech-design/"/>
    
      <category term="engine" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/engine/"/>
    
      <category term="gamemaker" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/gamemaker/"/>
    
      <category term="video" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/video/"/>
    
      <category term="destiny" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/destiny/"/>
    
      <category term="story" scheme="http://nvn.io/tags/story/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
